wsdot.com 2016-04-12

# WSDOT - Web Privacy Notice

### A. Introduction   

Thank you for visiting the Washington State Department of Transportation (WSDOT) web site and reviewing our Privacy Notice. This notice addresses the collection, use and security of and access to information that may be obtained through use of the WSDOT Web. 

This notice covers the following topics: 

Information Collected and How it is Used   
Personal Information and Choice   
Public Access to Information   
Nondisclosure of Certain Personal Information   
Review and Correction of Personally Identifiable Information   
Cookies   
Security   
Disclaimer   
Contact Information 

### B. Information Collected and How it is Used 

What information we collect if you only browse this site.   
If you do nothing during your visit to our web site but browse and read web pages, our web server will record certain information about your visit. None of this information is tied to your personal identity; you can browse our site anonymously. 

**We collect and store the following information about your visit:  
** The Internet Protocol Address and domain name used. The Internet Protocol address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. This address translates into the domain name of your service provider. (e.g. xcompany.com or yourschool.edu); 

The type of web browser software and operating system software you used;   
The date and time you visited this site;   
The web pages or services you accessed at this site; and   
The web site you visited prior to coming to this web site. 

The information WSDOT automatically collects is used only to help us understand how people are using our services. WSDOT analyzes this information to determine how our web site is being used, so that we may continually improve the site's usefulness to the public. 

**What information we collect if you volunteer it.**  
If during your visit to our web site you participate in a survey, send us email, download software, or perform some other transaction on-line, the following additional information will be collected: 

The email address, and contents of email, for those who communicate with us via email.   
Information volunteered in response to a survey.   
Information volunteered through an on-line form for any other purpose. 

The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us. 

We use your email to respond directly to you, to address issues you identify in your email, to further improve our web site, or to forward to another agency for appropriate action. Survey information is used to continually improve our services. Information from other on-line forms is used to provide you with a particular service. 

\-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

### C. Personal Information and Choice 

You may choose whether to provide personal information on-line. 

"Personal information" is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information. 

We do not collect personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending us e-mail or completing an on-line form. You may choose not to contact us by email or to provide any personal information using an on-line form. Your choice not to participate in these activities will not impair your ability to browse WSDOT Web and view the information provided on the site. 

If personal information is requested on the web site or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by state or federal law. 

If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact  WSDOT Customer Service as shown in the Contact Information section of this notice. 

Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children on-line or by email will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access. 

\-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

### D. Public Access to Information 

In Washington, laws exist to ensure that state government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs, including the privacy of individuals. Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws. 

All of the information collected at this site becomes public records that may be subject to inspection and copying by members of the public, unless an exemption in law exists. The provisions of RCW 42.56.070(1) state that: 

"Each agency, in accordance with published rules, shall make available for public inspection and copying all public records, unless the record falls within the specific exemptions of subsection (6) of this section, this chapter, or other statute which exempts or prohibits disclosure of specific information or records. To the extent required to prevent an unreasonable invasion of personal privacy interests protected by this chapter, an agency shall delete identifying details in a manner consistent with this chapter when it makes available or publishes any public record; however, in each case, the justification for the deletion shall be explained fully in writing." 

In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and the Public Records Act or other law governing the agency’s disclosure of records, the Public Records Act or other applicable law will control. 

\-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

### E. Nondisclosure of Certain Information 

WSDOT may require you to provide certain personal information in order to complete a specific transaction. The information is required in order to provide you with specific services. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to provide these services, and you will have to complete your transaction either in person or by mail. 

Although information collected at this site may be subject to public inspection, members of the general public do not have a right to inspect your credit card numbers, debit card numbers, electronic check numbers, card expiration dates, or bank or other financial account numbers that are supplied to an agency for the purpose of electronic transfer of funds, except when disclosure is expressly required by law. RCW 42.56.210(1). 

back to top   
\-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

### F. Review and Correction of Personally Identifiable Information 

You can review any personally identifiable information we collect about you by using the information in the Contact Information section at the end of this Notice. You may recommend changes to your personally identifiable information you believe to be inaccurate by submitting a written or email request that credibly shows the inaccuracy. We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. (RCW 43.105.310) 

\-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

### G. Cookies 

WSDOT uses "cookies" to customize your browsing experience on the WSDOT Web. Cookies are simple text files stored on your computer by your web browser. We use the cookie feature to store a randomly generated identifying tag on your computer that identifies your computer as a returning visitor to the WSDOT Web and allows you to keep the text size you specified by clicking on the smaller or larger text option. We also use a cookie that collects anonymous traffic data. 

If you choose to download software from WSDOT, we do request that you provide personal information so that we may offer software support. This information is collected from an online form and stored on your computer in the form of a cookie. While this cookie will simplify your process for obtaining additional software, you may elect to decline this cookie. 

back to top   
\-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

### H. Security 

WSDOT takes precautions to safeguard the personal information you provide through our web services. Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology with 128 bit encryption is used to ensure security. 

You must use a web browser that supports 128 bit encryption to use the areas on this web site that collect your personal and financial information. 

In 2007 the United States government's Computer Emergency Readiness Team (US-CERT) identified an increasing threat from software attacks that take advantage of vulnerable web browsers. US-CERT observed a trend whereby new software vulnerabilities are exploited and directed at web browsers through the use of compromised or malicious web sites. [US-CERT provides information to help you secure your web browser.](http://www.us-cert.gov/reading_room/securing_browser/)

This should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via WSDOT web sites. 

\-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

### I. Disclaimer 

The WSDOT Web has many links to other sites on the World Wide Web. These include links to sites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations, and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on the WSDOT Web and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another web site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site. 

Neither the State of Washington, nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State of Washington warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by this web site, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this web site, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this web site does so at their own risk. 

back to top   
\-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

### J. WSDOT Contact Information 

You may contact WSDOT as follows: 

To review your personal information, or request correction of your personal information, or if you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted  [send us feedback ](http://www.wsdot.wa.gov/contact/feedback.htm). 

\-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

Last updated: October 12, 2007
